## Maneesh Naidu

Suva, Fiji. +679 2032 419 maneesh.naidu@hotmail.com https://maneeshnaidu.github.io/portfolio

#### **OBJECTIVE**

A motivated individual with in-depth knowledge of languages and development tools, seeking a position in a growth-oriented company where I can use my skills to the advantage of the company while having the scope to develop my own skills.

#### PERSONAL STATEMENT

Software Developer/ Technical Consultant with almost 5 years of experience in developing enterprise applications using mainly SAP S/4HANA, JavaScript and .NET technologies. Seeking to leverage my technical and professional expertise to grow in the field of Computer Science and Information Systems.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Front-End Technologies \ Web Technologies: SAPUI5, JQuery JavaScript, XML, HTML5, CSS3, XMLASP.NET 4.5, MVC, Razor, AJAX, Bootstrap 3 \ WCF
- Architectural Pattern / Programming Languages: MVC, OOP \ ABAP, C#, JavaScript
- Database \ Data Access: HANA, MS SQL Server 2014, MYSQL \ OpenSQL, ADO.NET, LINQ to SQL, Entity Framework Core
- Web Servers \ Web Services: SAP NetWeaver Application Server, IIS \ HTTP
- Cloud Services \ Testing Tools: SAP S/4 HANA, MS Azure \ ABAP Test Cockpit, MS Visual Studio Test Tools, MAVEN Automation Testing
- Version Control Tools \ Methodology: SAP Transport, Git, Github \ Agile (Scrum)

## PERSONAL SKILLS

- Good oral and written communication ability.
- Self-confident, friendly and approachable with good presentation.
- Relate well with a wide variety of people.
- Responsible and reliable.
- Thorough knowledge in the areas of Computer Science and Information Systems.
- Dynamic, creative and enthusiastic in all things.
- Confident and strives to be the very best.
- Quick learner.
- Ability to work under pressure with minimum supervision.
- Strong leadership quality.
- Creative thinker.
- Multi-tasking and work with accuracy

#### **WORK HISTORY**

#### InvenioLSI

Suva 08/2021 - Present

#### **SAP Technical Consultant**

- Develop and implement technical specifications.
- Understand functional specifications.
- Full stack SAP development and implementation including SAPUI5, ABAP, Webdynpro, OData and BRF+ objects.
- Perform unit testing.
- Support other forms of testing.
- Support functional consultants in designing solutions for the gaps identified.
- Participate in and support implementations and developments.
- Attend and participate in internal knowledge sharing sessions.
- Research new and innovative solutions in the SAP areas

# Ministry of Agriculture, Fiji

Suva 04/2020 – 06/2021

## **Assistant Programmer/ IT Team Lead**

- Full stack web development using Dotnet technologies.
- Developing software tools to automate existing business processes prescribed by managers.
- Performing maintenance lifecycle programming for ongoing projects and software applications.
- Analyze and enhance the design and functionalities of the software systems.
- Database development and administration using MS SQL Server.
- Server administration.
- Documentation for software developed.
- Troubleshooting software and network issues.
- Software testing, modules testing and software deployment.
- Provide ongoing IT support.
- Email configuration, trouble shooting.

## SAAS (FIJI) LTD

Suva 01/2020 – 03/2020

## **Software Developer**

- Develop system functionalities both backend and frontend using Dotnet technologies.
- Analyze and enhance the design and functionalities of the software systems.
- Documentation for software developed.
- Provide ongoing system support.
- Troubleshooting software and network issues.
- Software testing, modules testing and software deployment.

#### QIT Pacific Pte Ltd

Suva

10/2019 - 12/2019

## **Software Developer**

- Develop system functionalities both backend and frontend using Dotnet technologies.
- Analyze and enhance the design and functionalities of the software systems.
- Documentation for software developed.
- Provide ongoing system support.
- Troubleshooting software issues.
- Software testing, modules testing and software deployment.

## Crimsonlogic Pte Ltd

Suva

04/2019 - 10/2019

## **Software Engineer**

- Analyse and test the DigitalFiji system and report errors or issues and identify possible solutions.
- Analyse and enhance the design and functionalities of the software systems.
- Writing SQL scripts for data patches in the backend which can't be done through system functionalities.
- Provide user training on the new systems built Birth Death Marriage (BDM) System and Register of Companies (ROC).
- Prepare system documentation and Standard Operating Procedures (SOPs) slides and diagrams for DigitalFiji modules.
- Provide ongoing system support.
- Troubleshooting software and network issues.
- Software testing, payment modules testing and software deployment

## Fijian Competition & Consumer Commision

Suva

01/2019 - 03/2019

## **IT Intern**

- Provide ongoing IT support.
- Email configuration, trouble shooting.
- Develop Web pages as per IT officer's/ Management's Requirements

## **QUALIFICATIONS**

## Fiji National University

Suva 2016 - 2018

#### **Bachelor of Science**

Computer Science and Information Systems

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- APO Digital Government Transformation Training Ministry of Agriculture Representative
- Runner Up of Smart City Challenge Suva Hackathon 2018 Team leader of Fiji National University Team

## **INTERESTS**

• Full marathon runner, enjoy playing futsal. Have represented Fijian youth and district football teams.

## **REFEREES**

Belinda Bithell
Senior Project Manager
InvenioLSI
+679 782 4872
belinda.bithell@inveniolsi.com

Francis Gomas
Web Engineer
ANZ Fiji
+679 722 1344
francis.gomas@anz.com